{Wise man Daniel is guided and regulated
by the living Word,
to minister Gods power of
deliverance, healing,
breakthrough and salvation
to the congregants during the
Synagogue Church of All Nation live service.
Christ power and goodness is neither scanty or scarce.
And manifests mightily through
the prayer and action of the wise man.
Destroying the work of the devil and every hidden agenda
in the lives of the people.
As he offers prayer in the name of Jesus Christ.
The light of God fell upon this man.
And began to wrestle his soul free from
the clutches of darkness.
Which had kept him in bondage
and disappointment for so long.
Watch as Jesus Christ rescues this
man through the prayer of wise man Daniel.}
(Fire, all over your body, you demon.
Fire in the Mighty name of Jesus Christ,
Who are you?)
I am marine spirit.
(How many are you in this body?)
We are many.
(Who is the second person?)
'Ogboni' cult.
(What have you done to him?)
I have destroyed him.
(How far have you gone?
what have you done to his career?
what do you do for a living?)
He is in entertainment.
What have you done to his career?
I have destroyed it.
I don't want him to succeed in anything he does.
(How far have you gone in destroying his career as a man?)
We will destroy anything he lay his hand upon.
(You have destroy anything he lay his hand upon?)
Yes.
(What have you done to his marital life?)
We have given him the spirit of lust.
(How has the spirit of lust affected him?)
He uses his eyes to see women;
he sleeps with very woman he sees.
A lot of women.
(What happen to those women - their career
As soon I sleep with them, anything he does fails.
(Does it mean those women are your agents?)
Yes, anything he does fails.
(Listen to me, You send those to women to him?)
Yes, to destroy him.
(How has the spirit of anger affected him?)
A lot.
(How?)
He is very stubborn, he fights
anybody that cross his way.
(You make him fight any
body that crosses his way?
And when you fight what
happens to this people?)
Before he knows it, he finds himself where he doesn't expect to be.
(Can you give instances of places he finds himself after fighting?)
He fights policemen everyday in Ghana
if he is driving.
Nobody can come to him, anywhere.
(What would happen to him at the end of the day?)
He will end up spending all his
money where he is not supposed to spend.
On things that are not necessary.
(what have you done to his family?)
He is supposed to be the pillar of his family
he is a great person.
(Look here!
Open your eyes.
Thank you Lord in Jesus name.
Thank you Lord you are free!
How are you?}
I am fine.
(What happened to you?)
I am dirty,
(Why?)
I don't know.
I sat here.
(You were standing there?)
Yes
(Who pushed you down?
you just stood from the floor)
Thank you Jesus!
Emmanuel!
My name is Chris Paul Abure.
I am a Nigerian living in Ghana.
By my right here is my mum.
beside my mum is her sister.
Those are my two younger sisters.
I am a professional model:
I am a model by profession
I am here to that God for what He has done in my life.
It all happened 16 years ago.
I didn't know what I did to my dad, I offended him.
He called me in a room for one on one,
and he removed his clothes and cursed me.
He said to me that I will never prosper in anything I do.
I did find it funny then, i thought maybe he was joking.
I didn't take it serious.
I started acting funny since then
I was no longer stayed at home,
I started doing things I wasn't supposed to do.
I found my self smoking, I smoked a lot.
I used to dink and womanize.
I found myself doing things that were funny , I don't know.
One day, I felt like smoking; there was a spirit pushing me.
to go to the beach to smoke.
So I went to the beach and started smoking.
I was sitting on the beach alone smoking.
There was nobody in the beach, the place was quiet
that day was not a beach day that people come around.
As I was smoking, before I knew I just saw a beautiful coming from behind me.
And she tapped me on my back.
She said, "Handsome, how are you doing?"
I said, "Yeah, I am good."
Before I knew she joined me.
She started asking me what was my name.
Before she asked me what is my name,
we started kissing each other.
I didn't know her before.
We started kissing and enjoying what was happening.
Because she was very beautiful
It was not in the dream, It was physical.
She told me that we should take a walk.
I said, "I don't feel like, I'm okay where
I am right now."
I told here, If she wants to sit, she should sit.
If she doesnt feel like sitting, she should leave.
The next thing, as soon as I used that word
that I didn't feel like walking that
I was okay were I was.
The beach water was very far from me,
Before I uttered that word, the next
thing I saw was water in front of me.
I said, "Ah, what is this?"
The girl asked, "Whats wrong with you?"
She said that very soon she will
take me to where I belong.
As soon as she said that she will take me where I belong,
I asked her, "Where did I belong?"
I said, "I bind you in Jesus name"
but I was smoking.
I said, "I bind you in Jesus name."
Above everything, I believe in God.
But I couldnt stop my lifestyle.
I smoked alot and womanised
If I set my eyes on any girl,
unless I don't want her, she couldn't escape,
I must get her down.
I slept with every girl that came close to me.
I slept with a lot- I cant even count.
But I thank God for today.
{So that demon spirit,
affected you with the demon of what?}
Lust and anger
These big things happened three
times in my life
and in three different countries.
It happened here in Nigeria,
in Seirra Leone and in Ghana
{So each time you are sitting at the beach,
a strange lady would just come to you?}
She just walked down to me and we would start kissing.
But the last one, I didnt kiss her
the last one in Ghana, I didnt kiss her.
I said, "I know who you are."
I told her to leave me, I knew who she was.
And she said, "That she will get me."
There was a day in 2011 I was having a show
After the show, the girl just walked down to me
and called me by my name actually.
' Chris' and by my sir name ,Abure' and
I was wondering how she knew my sir name,
I haven't put my sir name on Facebook.
People knew me with the name' Chris'
and I put my other name which is 'Abolume'
I asked her, "How do you know my name?"
But I didn't mind because the girl was beautiful.
I just took her to the house,
When I took her in my house, just about to do anything
Something came in me and I said, "Thank you Jesus."
I don't know what happened, I cant remember
All i remember is I just said, Thank you Jesus!"
Before ending the thing, the girl said, "Leave me, leave me,"
She wanted to go, she was packing her things.
I said, "Where are you going? lets finished what we started."
She was saying, "No don't touch me., there is fire "
She was running from me.
She told me, "You are lucky, you are lucky!"
I asked her, "What do you mean by I am lucky,
what did you want to do to me?"
I started threatening her saying,
""you cannot do anything to me."
Those are my pictures,
I have done a couple of shows - commercial.
Sometimes when I do shows, I get angry with everybody.
Nobody could talk to me.
If anybody got in my way, I could fight them.
The spirit of anger made me in a way -
sometimes I could find myself in prison.
I could be drinking beer and someone makes me angry
I would just break the bottle and stub the person.
I have spent three weeks in prison in Burkina Faso
In a foreign country.
I have been in prison in Guinea, Conakry and Mali.
At the end of the day, they would just leave me there
because I don't have the money to bail me out.
But I still found myself doing the same thing.
I knew I had a problem, but I didn't know the way out.
It affected me a lot.
Sometimes if I go to the designers - boss, maybe they have a job for me,
as soon I get to them, they would tell me that
they have given the job to someone else already that deserves the job,
better than me.
Sometimes I would go to auditions, and they would pick me
that I would be doing the commercial, maybe is a big one.
and I am playing the key role.
As soon I get the job and everything is confirmed that I would do the job
the next morning they would change their minds.
I really have a lot of bad dreams.
Sometimes If I didn't sleep with a girl on that particular night,
I would dream having sex with that particular girl in the dream.
Sometimes I would me dreaming and see myself in my old school.
All those kinds of funny dreams, my old house.
I usually dream those kind of dreams alot.
{Okay, tell us, what effort did you find
to get a solution to your problem
before you eventually come to SCOAN?}
I have been in lot of places, I have been
in spiritual houses
from far, in find of a solution.
Because I knew I had a problem,
I saw myself not moving forward.
There are a lot of people that started with me
and they are very far unlike me.
And because of that i searched for solution,
but it was zero.
It all happened last year.
Actually I will not lie to you, I did not believe in Prophet TB Joshua before.
But it happened last year,
I usually saw what the Man of God was doing on TV.
I started watching, sometimes i would come across him preaching on TV.
doing healings and all this kinds of things
I watched the miracles.
One day in the office, my elder brother; all of them have anointed water
He gave me anointed water and I took some,
and I felt some funny movement inside my body.
I felt funny way in my body, I didn't know what was happening.
That night was on a Thursday,
Thursday in Ghana happens to be a reggae day in some places.
I went there.
I usually go to smoke before I could go and do my performances.
As I was about to smoke, I couldn't feel the smoke anymore
I didnt feel like smoking
It happened like that, and that is how since the middle
of last year i stopped smoking.
{So you mean after your elder brother gave you the anointed water,
and you took the anointed water and ministered to yourself
the urge to smoke disappeared?}
Yes exactly!
{Tell us, you were telling us a while ago about the experience
you used to have at the beach side.
A strange lady would just walk at you each time at the the side of the beach
what happened to you in your career, in your life?}
It happened that If I was going anywhere,
I didn't prosper in anything that I did
If I met anyone - it was failure.
The good things that I was supposed to get, they wouldn't get.
They would be giving me the lower ones which i was not okay with it.
I knew I had a problem.
It happened two weeks ago, i dreamt for the first time in my dream,
seeing Prophet TB Joshua delivering me in the dream
I woke up and wondered, "This man of God delivering me in the dream?"
That means I am delivered from my problems.
I told my elder brother, "I dreamt the Man of God delivering me in my dream."
He said, "you still need to go, you still need deliverance."
That is how I found my way to the church.
{And could you remember anything that happened
when the wise men were moving around, what happened?}
I didn't know what happened I just found myself on the floor.
they said, I say something.
No
{And after the deliverance tell us how you felt
immediately and since then, tell us your condition now?}
Since then I am a different person now, I don't feel the way i used to.
Because before when i was sitting alone I could think evil.
Nothing but evil, I would be thinking of how i would bring evil to people.
the is the only thing that could come into my mind.
something evil - bad things.
And since the deliverance I don't thing anymore.
The spirit of anger - Even if you slap me right now, I wouldn't return it.
I would say thank you!
{And the spirit of lust that has ruled and ruin your life,
tell us, since after you deliverance?}
Since then I don't feel anything, for any girl anymore - minus my wife.
Any other, even if she is beautiful.
My name is Mrs Abure
The one beside me is my son.
This woman is my younger sister.
Those two girls are my daughters.
I just want to thank God
because since my son called me,
He called me a day before the day we came to SCOAN.
He said, "Mummy I am coming to Nigeria for a program."
I was happy and said, "Okay pray for us."
He called me and told me that they have delivered him
we even saw him on the Emmanuel television live stream.
Because my son, his elder brother, when he came from Nigeria,
he said to me, "Mummy you dont have Emmanuel TV."
I said, "no!"
He paid money and they came and installed TV for me.
Since then, I have been watching, till day break.
24 hours a day - used to put it on.
My son called me saying, "Christopher is manifesting."
I asked, "Ah, my son is manifesting?"
We turned on Emmanuel TV.
At night we called him after delivering him.
He said, "Yes I have been delivered."
Previously, he was very stubborn, when his elder brother came from Nigeria,
he reported to me that no body could talk to him.
That the life he was living was a wayward life.
When you talk to him he was ready to fight that person.
He is ready to break the bottle and stub that person
Since he was delivered, I was very happy.
I am the happiest woman in the while world.
{Let us put our hands together for Jesus!
That says it all, 'mama' says that she is the happiest woman in the world today.
Since her son complitly delivered from his past ways of life.
That gives her peace, joy and comfort.
we thank God for her life, and can we hear from the aunt?}
My name is Comfort Wiyas
I thank God for his life.
We are all happy.
Thank you Jesus! Emmanuel!
{We are happy with you,
Let us clap for Jesus one more time!}
{With what the Lord has done in your life,
you have come a long way through life.
Now what kind of advice or encouragement
do you have to the people who are listening to your testimony
and also to the people who are in the same profession as you.
knowing the kind of life that they live outside there.
Now that you have seen the light,
what word of advice do you have for them?}
I know that there is a lot of people watching me right now.
My advice to them is that you should stick to Gods Word.
He will never fail them.
If you can listen to my story and see all I have passed through
It was not easy
Sometimes you may see yourself doing some funny things,
you would think that its fun, or enjoyment, or see your
self being with some pretty girls and smoking.
Those things are demonic.
Its not the real you doing those things.
So you need to be delivered, all you need is your freedom.
If you are not delivered, there is nothing that will be working well.
Things maybe working well for you right now,
and you may think maybe its by grace.
But all you need right now is to seek the face of God.
And if you do that, you life will never remain the same again.
Amen.
{Thank you very much, lets clap for Jesus!
wonderful advice, thank you.}